i got my first job when i was 15.
for about seven dollars an hour i helped
a librarian sort books and process
returns
later after university i lived in a city
and worked in an independent bookstore
for 11.50 an hour
i struggled to find a job that made me
enough money so that i could live
independently
so i worked multiple jobs and freelanced
my editing and writing skills and sold
art
at craft fairs after a couple years
i was doing okay but found myself
constantly worrying
and stressed about money
and then some horrible events happened
in my life that are still
too hard to talk about but despite the
pain they brought i learned how
important it was to not only be
emotionally but financially prepared
for unexpected life circumstances
i also realized that while i enjoyed my
current job and loved my co-workers
with my personal situation and goals i
wouldn't be able to move ahead to a more
stable future
if i stayed where i was
so feeling completely defeated at adult
life
and dealing with horrible anxiety i
called up my lifeline
and i talked to my mommy i cried and i
asked for help i had applied and been
accepted in the position of a preschool
teacher
in their town i wanted to come home i
missed her and my papi
i needed help with transportation and
covering basic costs until i began my
new job
it was so hard to ask this of them and i
felt so disappointed in myself
[Music]
um
i've had friends tell me it is
embarrassing to ask for help from your
family
and that it's more impressive to do
things on one's own
i even get comments similar to these
online that getting family support is
failing somehow at adulthood and
sometimes even shameful
it is ironic since so many young people
have no choice but to rely on others to
make ends meet in our current world
and while it is a privilege to have
people in your life that can help you in
times of need
there's absolutely no shame in accepting
support when you need it
in my case it made all the difference in
changing my life for the better
using my savings to help me relocate my
father covered my health insurance and
helped me transition into my new job
as a developing rural area my town was
in great need of construction workers
and plumbers and
thankfully teachers my salary as a child
care worker was still not very much
and while i was able to finally cover my
monthly costs more easily
i still feared unforeseen expenses such
as my car breaking down
so i decided to try turning my art into
a side business
farmers markets are not considered a
lucrative endeavor in most places but
i was lucky because my town experiences
a lot of tourism
and many of the crafters and farmers
that sell there are able to make it a
part-time job
i saw this and thought it would be a
great way to supplement my income
and feel more independent and it worked
i got wonderful feedback on my art and
encouraged me to consider opening up a
shop
online things started so
slowly with my online business i didn't
know how to get my work noticed
i set myself a challenge of one year to
deal with the life of running a business
working at markets and at the preschool
it was a lot
but little by little things were looking
up i was getting sales and working
overtime at the school
i was so excited for the future but then
last march happened
and my country shut down i found myself
temporarily out of a job
and i was terrified that my school would
close for good
and i would have to move back to the
city trying to ignore my fear
i started looking for ways to get
creative with my time off
it was wildflower season after all and i
decided i would find a way to share some
of the beauty of this valley
with those who couldn't visit hoping to
bring some peaceful moments to others
who
felt like me
[Music]
do
so it was luke's birthday this week and
so i wanted to make him a pie
i was really proud of how it had turned
out and i put it in the oven and about
30 minutes in
i realized that i never put an air vent
in the pie
and when you don't put air vents in pies
they explode the filling
bubbled up around the edges and it
definitely does not look as beautiful as
it could have
but i found that the moment you can
start laughing at your mistakes in life
everything gets better thankfully it
does not affect
the taste of the pie which is the most
important part
obviously i don't make pies that often
or i would have remembered this
very very basic step
[Music]
it was in april that i pulled out my
iphone and bought a very cheap tripod
that i almost immediately had to replace
making videos was a thoughtful and
peaceful process that made me feel like
just maybe tomorrow would be a bit
better and brighter
it was tricky to learn how to be both
the cameraman and in the shots
but over time i improved by the end of
the year i'd gotten a wonderful response
and been able to connect with so many
lovely people
my school partially reopened and i
started my work as a teacher again
and this time i was able to supplement
my income through my job online
i was and am forever grateful for that
and now one year after my future
suddenly became so uncertain
i'm taking another great leap after much
deliberation
i realized that while i did want to keep
teaching i specifically wanted to be an
art teacher
so recently i transitioned out of my
preschool and started making new plans
for the future
there are a lot of unknowns but i'm
learning to embrace it
as that is where sparks of innovation
are born
of course i would love to hear below
about your own journey with your career
or careers as in my case i'm wishing you
all the best
and sending hope for a brighter future
i'll see you next week
[Music]
you